I have a dream
我有一个梦想
A song to sing
有这么一首歌
To help me cope
能帮助我克服万难
With anything
成就所有的事情
If you see the wonder
如果你见过童话中的
Of a fairy tale
奇迹
You can take the future
你就能掌握未来
Even if you fail.
就算你失败了
Sam Carmichael.
Bill Anderson.
Harry Bright.
Gentlemen, I have to go.
各位，我得走了。
Thank you very much. Take care.
非常感谢，保重。
Morning, Rodney.
早啊，Rodney。
Taxi!
出租车！
JFK, please, as quick as you can.
肯尼迪机场(纽约国际机场），越快越好。
片名《妈妈咪呀》
译者：Yankie Yan 校订： Perry Zhang
Version 0.2
For All My Friends!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
噢，我的天呐！噢，我的天呐！
I missed you. Oh, no...
我想死你了，哦，不对...
We're...
我们是。。。
Sophie, Ali, Lisa! We're the greatest, bestest mates!
Sophie, Ali,Lisa!我们是最最要好的死党！
I'm tough.         I'm tall.
我强壮。   我高挑。
I'm tiny.         And we're gonna rock this place.
我娇小。   我们要撼天动地。
Sophie, it's beautiful.         I want one.
Sophie,好漂亮的戒指。  我也想要嘛。
He did well, didn't he?
他很能干嘛，对不对？
I'm getting married tomorrow.
我明天就要结婚了。
I'm so glad you're here,
你们能来我好高兴啊，
because I have a secret and I can't tell anybody else.
因为我有一个不能告诉其他人的秘密
Sophie, you're knocked up?         No! No! No!
Sophie,你有喜了啊？   没有！没有！没有！
I've invited my dad to my wedding.
我请了我的爹地来参加我的婚礼。
You are joking!
你在说笑！
You found him at last?
你终于找到他了？
No! No, no, no, no, no, not exactly.
不！不，不，不，不，不能这么说。
Okay. You know what my mom always said when I asked about my father.
OK。你们知道当我问起我父亲时我妈老是说什么吧。
It was a summer romance,
那是一段夏天的罗曼史。
and he'd gone long before she realised that she was expecting me.
当他离开很久之后她才意识到有了我。
And I'd always kind of accepted that that's all I'd ever know.
而我一直有那么点相信了这些她告诉我的就是事实的全部。
Well, I was ransacking some old trunks and I found this.
可是，在我翻箱倒柜搜刮的时候找到了这个。
It's the diary she kept the year she was pregnant with me.
是她怀上我那年的日记。
Sophie!
"July 17th. What a night!"
“七月十七日。多么美妙的一夜啊！”
I don't know if I want to hear this!         I do!
我都不知道自己要不要听这个呢！   我要！
"Sam rowed me over to the little island."
"Sam划着船带我来到这么个小岛。"
That's here. That's Kalokairi.
“就是这里。Kalokairi.”
"We danced on the beach, and we kissed on the beach,
"我们在沙滩上跳舞，然后接吻，
"and dot, dot, dot."
然后 点，点，点。"
What?
不是吧？
"Dot, dot, dot." That's what they did in the olden days.
“点，点，点。”古时候他们就是这么说的。
Stop it!
别念了啦！
"Sam's the one. I know he is.
"Sam是我的真命天子。肯定是
"I've never felt like this before."
“我从来没有过这种感觉。”
Honey, honey
甜心，甜心
How he thrills me Honey, honey
他让我兴奋到不行，甜心，甜心
Honey, honey
甜心，甜心
Nearly kills me Honey, honey
差点就不行，甜心，甜心
I've heard about him before
之前我有听人提起过他
I wanted to know some more
我曾想了解更多
And now I know what they mean
现在我知道他们的意思了
He's a love machine
他是一架爱情机器
Oh, he makes me dizzy
Oh,他让我神魂颠倒
Honey, honey Let me feel it
甜心，甜心，带我去感受它吧
Honey, honey
甜心，甜心
Honey, honey Don't conceal it
甜心，甜心不要掩饰了
Honey, honey
甜心，甜心
The way that you kiss good night
晚上你吻安的方式
The way that you kiss me good night
晚上你吻我晚安的方式
The way that you hold me tight
你紧拥我的方式
The way that you're holding me tight
你紧拥着我的方式
I feel like I wanna sing
我想要歌唱
When you do your thing
当你做这事的时候
So this guy Sam's your father!
这么说这个叫Sam的就是你父亲咯！
The plot thickens.
没那么简单。
"All this time, Sam's been telling me he loves me,
“一直以来，Sam都跟我说他爱我，”
"and now he's announced that he's engaged,
“现在他却宣布他已经订婚了，
"so he's gone home to get married,
“所以他回家成婚去了，
"and I'm never going to see him again."
"我再也见不到他了。”
Poor Donna.
Donna真可怜.
"August 4th. What a night!
“八月四日。多么美妙的一夜啊！
"Bill rented a motorboat, and I took him over to the little island."
“Bill租了一艘摩托艇，然后我带他去了那座小岛。”
Bill? Sophie, wait.         Hang on.
Bill?Sophie,等等。   打住。
"Though I'm still obsessed with Sam,
“尽管我当时还对Sam余情未了，”
"Bill's so wild. He's such a funny guy.
“Bill好狂野啊。他是个相当风趣的家伙。
"One thing led to another,
“一波未平，一波又起
"and dot, dot, dot."
“然后点，点，点。”
"August 11th. Harry turned up, out of the blue,
“八月十一日。Harry突然出现了，从天而降，
"so I said I'd show him the island.
“于是我说我想带他去那座岛。”
"He's so sweet and understanding, I couldn't help it and
“他是那么迷人且善解人衣，我控制不住了，接着
"dot, dot, dot!"
“点，点，点！”
Oh, my God!         Here come the bridesmaids.
Oh，我的上帝啊！   伴娘们驾到了啊。
Donna!
Look at you!
瞧瞧你们俩！
God! Stop growing!
上帝！别再长大了！
You sound like you're having fun already.         Oh, we are.
听起来你们俩好像已经快活过了。  呵,的确如此。
I used to have fun.
我也曾经快活过。
Oh, we knew!
Oh,我们早知道了！
Honey, honey Touch me, baby
甜心，甜心抚摸我吧，宝贝
Honey, honey
甜心，甜心
Honey, honey Hold me, baby
甜心，甜心抱紧我，宝贝
Honey, honey
甜心，甜心
You look like a movie star
你就像个电影明星
But I love just who you are
可是我只爱内在的你
And, honey, to say the least
还有，甜心，再说一句
You're a doggone beast
你简直就是个野兽
Bugger!
贱人！
My sentiments exactly.
我完全同感。
So, who is your dad?
那么，谁才是你爹地？
Sam, Bill or Harry?         I don't know.
Sam, Bill 还是 Harry?      我不清楚。
But which one did you invite?
那么你到底邀请了谁啊？
Oh, my God!
奥，卖，糕！
Do they know?         What would you write to a total stranger?
他们知道吗？     你能对完全陌生的人写些什么呢？
"Please come to my wedding, you might be my father"? No.
“请来参加我的婚礼，你可能是我的父亲”?不。
They think that Mom sent the invites, and with what's in here,
他们以为是我妈发的请柬，由于有了这些猛料
no surprise they said yes!
也就难怪他们都答应要来啊。
Honey, honey How you thrill me
甜心，甜心你让我兴奋到不行
Honey, honey
甜心，甜心
Honey, honey Nearly kill me
甜心，甜心让我差点就不行
Honey, honey
甜心，甜心
I'd heard about you before
之前我有听人提起过你
I wanted to know some more
我曾想了解更多
And now I'm about to see
现在我自己就要
What you mean to me
知道你对我意味着什么了
I'm trying to get to Kalokairi. When's the next ferry?
我正急着要赶去Kalokairi。下趟船是什么时候？
What?         Monday.
什么？    礼拜一。
Bollocks!         Yeah, my sentiments exactly.
卵子！   耶,我完全同感。
Bride or groom?
新娘还是新郎？
Bride, although I've actually never met her.
新娘，不过我跟她还素未谋面。
Ahoy, there.
喂。
You guys need a ride to Kalokairi?
你们两个要搭船去Kalokairi吗？
Excuse me, coming through. I have a senior citizen with me. Thank you.
抱歉，借过。给这位老人家让个路吧。谢谢。
My mother needs a perch.
我母亲需要个地方好落脚。
Mother? We're the same age.
母亲？我们是同龄人啊。
Yeah. Well, parts of us are.
唔，这样啊，部分是吧。
Sailor.
水手。
No.
不。
Oh, he has your book!
呵，他有你的书啊。
Stavros, Stavros.
Stavros.
给Stavros。
It's just a fish.
不就是条鱼嘛。
You are so clever.
你真乖巧。
We're going to look fabulous tomorrow.
我们明天一定会很耀眼喏。
I want the perfect wedding, and I want my father to give me away.
我要一个完美的婚礼，我要我的父亲将我托付出去。
Better be a wide aisle.
教堂的过道最好宽一些。
I will know my father as soon as I see him.
谁是我的父亲我一看就知道。
Sky! Come here, gorgeous.
Sky!过来，俊男。
Put me down. I'm getting married tomorrow.
放倒我吧。我明天就要结婚了。
Please be careful.
请注意了。
So? There are pins in the dresses.
那又怎么样？婚纱上有别针。
What do you think?
你看怎么样？
Oh, yes!
噢，yes！
"Oh, yes." If you had your way,
“噢，yes。”如果用你的办法的话，
it'd be a threeminute wedding in jeans and Tshirts,
那婚礼肯定是穿个牛仔裤加T恤3分钟就搞定了，
washed down with a bottle of beer.
再来瓶啤酒从头淋下来。
You make me sound so unromantic!
你说得我好像一点都不懂浪漫似的！
I just thought we should save our money for travelling.
我只想把钱存下来好去旅行嘛。
Well, we're not going anywhere yet.
是吗？我们现在还没打算好要去哪里呢。
Anyway, please leave. We're very, very busy.
别说了，请退下。我们非常，非常忙。
I'm just getting some props for tonight.
我只是为了晚上的活动上来拿些装备.
For his bachelor party.
为了他的单身汉晚会。
Why haven't you told him you've invited your dads?
你为什么还没告诉他你有请你的爹地们来呢？
Because he would say that I'd have to tell my mom.
因为他会让我告诉我妈的。
Donna's absolutely gonna kill you when she finds out.
Donna知道了一定会杀了你的。
By the time she finds out, it'll be too late.
当她知道的时候，已经太迟了。
I feel like there's a part of me missing,
我总觉得我的生命不完整，
and when I meet my dad,
当我跟我爹地相见后，
everything will fall into place.
就会破镜重圆了。
More open! I'm on it. I'm on it.
再放开些！马上，马上。
That's good.
很好。
That's it.
就这样最好。
Come on, Cleopatra.
快点呐，埃及艳后。
My shoe!
我的鞋！
Will you look at what the tide washed in?
你们瞧瞧海浪都把什么冲来了啊？
For one night.         And one night only.
一晚。      只要一晚。
Donna and the Dynamos!
Donna 与 Dynamos妹力十足!
Look at you!
瞧瞧你！
You baby!         Look at you!
你这个宝贝！  瞧瞧你！
You look fantastic!
你看起来真美极了！
You look like an old hippie!
你看起来像老嬉皮士！
She looks fab.
她很靓。
These are new, though. Where did you get these?
它们很新啊。谁给你弄的？
Husband number three!
第三号丈夫！
Dynamos! Dynamite!
妹力四射！魅力四射！
Sleep all day and...
每日每夜
All night!
都呼呼大睡！
So, any men at this wedding?
对了，这次婚礼有男人吗？
Gorgeous Greeks of independent means?
单身的希腊俊男意味着？
Here we go! Husband number four!
我们冲啊！第四号丈夫！
No! Not for me, for her!
不！我不要，给她吧！
For her, now that her book is a bestseller,
给她，现在她的书最畅销了，
and she's got the whole world stuffing, what,
她现在什么都有了，比如那个什么，
mushrooms? Various vegetables?
蘑菇？各种各样的蔬菜？
It's time to find Mr Right!
是时候该有个真命天子了！
Oh, please. Boring!
啊，饶了我吧。无聊！
Great couple of role models you two are for Sophie!
你们两个真不愧是Sophie的好模范啊！
A serial bride and a little hermit over here!
一个新娘惯犯和一个小独居者。
That's me! I'm a lone wolf!
没错！我就是只独狼！
So, when are the lovebirds flying the nest?
那两只比翼鸟什么时候筑巢呢？
Oh, God! Who knows?
噢，只有上帝知道。
You know, I do not know what is going on in that child's head sometimes.
听我说，我有时候根本不知道那孩子都想些什么。
She wants a big white wedding, and
她想要一个盛大的婚礼，然后
she and Sky are making all kinds of plans for the hotel.
她跟Sky为这家酒店做着各种打算。
Sometimes I think they'll never leave.
有时候我还以为他们永远也不想离开呢。
Yeah, but do you really want her to?
对，可你真想她离开吗？
Well, I want what's best for her.
我只想什么对她才是最好的。
Of course not!
当然不想啦！
Sky! Come meet my backup girls.
Sky!快来见见我的候补女孩们。
Backup girls, my ass! Backup girls, my ass!
候补女孩个屁啊！候补女孩个屁啊！
He's the leading man at tomorrow's shindig.
他就是明天狂欢的那个男主角。
The lucky man.
那个幸运的家伙。
You must be Rosie.         I am.
你肯定是Rosie.   正是。
How are you?         Very well.
别来无恙。   还好。
And you must be Tanya.
那你一定是Tanya。
I've heard so much about you.         All bad, I hope.
久仰大名。        我希望全是坏名。
Yes.         And all true.
你说是。         全是真的。
Donna... Here, let me get them.
Donna。。。 让我来吧。
I know who you are. You're Bill Anderson, aren't you?
我知道你是谁。 你是Bill Anderson，对吧？
Bloke in a Boat in Botswana.         Yes, I am.
独自航行在博茨瓦纳的家伙。  正是本人。
You know, your books are a godsend on dull business trips.
你的书对乏味的商业旅行者来说简直就是天赐之物
Now, I may look like I'm pondering my securities, but in reality,
现在，也许我正杞人忧天，可事实上，
I'm trekking across some remote corner of the planet.
我正跋涉于这星球的某个不毛之地。
You should try it for real sometime.
你也该真的去尝试一下了。
No, certainly, I'll never be the spontaneous adventurer.
当然不想，我从来就不会自发地去冒险的。
You're a close friend of Donna's?         No, I haven't heard from her for 20 years.
你是Donna的挚友？   不，我从没和她联络过，快20年了吧。
Really?         And then this invite, out of the blue.
是吗？   然后就从天而降了这么个邀请。
You know, that's a coincidence, neither had I.
真是个巧合，我也完全是这种情况。
Going about!         You got it!
开动吧！  没问题！
Right. Wait... I've got it. Fine. Fine.
好，别。。。我抓到了。好了。好了。
You should have brought the iron lung.
你应该把你的铁肺带来的。
Why did I wear stilettos?
为什么我要穿高跟鞋？
Oxygen.         Oh, my God!
氧气。  奥卖糕！
Auntie Rosie!
Rosie阿姨！
Look at Sophie. She's gotten so beautiful!
快瞧Sophie。她越长越漂亮了啊！
Come here to me.
过来我抱抱。
Sophie Sheridan, you get more gorgeous every time I see you. You do.
Sophie Sheridan，你真是女大十八变啊！
I bet you don't remember me.
我打赌你不记得我了。
Not with all that plastic surgery.
那还不都是因为那些塑胶整形手术啊。
Of course I do, Auntie Tanya. You haven't changed at all.
我当然记得你啦，Tanya阿姨。你一点没变。
Look at my baby,
瞧瞧我的宝贝，
her whole life ahead of her.
她前程似锦。
Oh, please, I'm getting married. I'm not joining a convent!
噢，饶了我吧，我要结婚，不要进修道院！
She's feisty. I love that.
她很有活力，我喜欢。
She's a chip off the old block.
有其母必有其女。
If she were more like me, she wouldn't be getting married at 20.
要是她更像我的话，她就不会20岁就结婚了。
Or married at all.
或许根本就不会结婚。
I meant to get the laundry down before you came.
我本来要在你们来之前把衣服收起来的。
Tanya's going home!
Tanya回家咯！
And you'd think with all this new technology,
你以为现在科技这么发达，
they would figure out a machine that would make the beds.
他们或许能造出一架整理床的机器。
And if they did, you'd be going along behind it,making them again.
要是他们真造了，你也会在它们整理完之后，再整理一次的。
I know you, Mom.
我了解你，妈妈。
But I am good at modern... Tell them about the Internets.
但我很了解现代。。。跟她们说说互联网。
He's gonna put me on the line.         Online.
他要把我放在网上去。  在线。
I'm designing a website.
我正在设计一个网站。
I just think this place has so much potential,
我只是想这个地方有这么多的潜力，
and no one knows we're here.
然而却没有人知道我们在这里。
So, if I market it really, really well, then, hopefully, people will come flooding in.
所以，要是我营销做的非常非常好的话，人们很有可能潮水般蜂拥而至的。
We just want this to be the ultimate romantic destination.
我们就想把这打造成终极浪漫的旅游目的地。
This was once supposed to be the site of Aphrodite's fountain,
过去盛传这里是维纳斯（罗马神话）喷泉的遗址。
you know, the goddess of love. And if you drank the water,
就是那个爱神。如果你喝了这个泉水的话，
you were supposed to find true love and perfect happiness.
就能找到真爱和完美的幸福。
I'll have a glass of that.         Yeah, I'll have a bucket.
那我得喝一杯。              嗯，我要一桶。
Aphrodite's spa?
维纳斯的spa?
Well, I thought you didn't want boatloads of tourists.
我以为你不想要满载的游客呢。
Oh, no, not boatloads, no.
噢，不，满载就不用了。
But, you know, a few more would be nice.
但是，有几个就好了。
Okay, now, the thing about the toilet,
OK，关于厕所的问题，
if it doesn't flush right away,
如果它没有自动冲水的话，
just go and come back in a while, and it should...
你只要离开一会儿再回来，它应该可以。。。
Nothing works around here, except for me.
这里没什么能用的了，除了我。
I've been running this hotel for 15 years, and I have never had a day off.
我经营这家旅店15年了，从来就没休过假。
Oh, my God! Sorry.
噢，我的天！抱歉。
I work all night I work all day
我每日每夜的工作
To pay the bills I have to pay
为了付清账单
Ain't it sad?
很悲惨啊！
And still there never seems to be A single penny left for me
却从来没有看到一个子儿剩下
Don't sit down there.
别做那。
That's too bad
真的很惨
It's broken.
椅子坏了。
In my dreams I have a plan
我在梦中有个计划
If I got me a wealthy man
要是我能找个富翁
I wouldn't have to work at all
我就不用工作了
I'd fool around and have a ball
我要开个舞会然后沾花惹草
Money, money, money
有钱，钱，钱
Must be funny
一定很爽
In a rich man's world
在有钱人的世界里
Money, money, money
有钱，钱，钱
Always sunny
就能永浴阳光
In a rich man's world
在有钱人的世界里
All the things I could do
我能随心所欲
If I had a little money
如果我能有点钱
It's a rich man's world
这是个有钱人的世界
A man like that is hard to find
那种男人很难找
But I can't get him off my mind
但我难以忘却
Ain't it sad?
真伤脑筋
And if he happens to be free
就算他是单身
I bet he wouldn't fancy me
我打赌他也不会喜欢我
That's too bad
那可真糟
So I must leave I have to go
那么我得离开这里
To Las Vegas or Monaco
去拉斯维加斯或者摩纳哥
And win a fortune in a game
一把赢个够
My life will never be the same
我这辈子就改变了
Money, money, money
有钱，钱，钱
Must be funny
一定很爽
In a rich man's world
在有钱人的世界里
Money, money, money
有钱，钱，钱
Always sunny
就能永浴阳光
In a rich man's world
在有钱人的世界里
All the things I could do
我能随心所欲
If I had a little money
如果我能有点钱
It's a rich man's world
这是个有钱人的世界
Money, money, money
有钱，钱，钱
Must be funny
一定很爽
In a rich man's world
在有钱人的世界里
Money, money, money
有钱，钱，钱
Always sunny
就能永浴阳光
In a rich man's world
在有钱人的世界里
All the things I could do
我能随心所欲
If I had a little money
如果我能有点钱
It's a rich man's world
这是个有钱人的世界
What's going on?
怎么了？
Do you feel it?
你们感觉到了吗？
The earth moved, darling. We're falling apart here.
刚才地动了一下，亲爱的。我们差点就掉下去了。
Don't think about it, come on. Let's go have fun.
别想了，走。我们快活去。
Tanya's packed for a world tour.
Tanya以为环球旅行来了。
Oh, Donna. Donna!
啊，Donna. Donna!
Does she wear it or floss with it?
她到底是用来穿还是用来剔牙？
Floss you.
剔你个头啊。
Is it edible, Tanya?
还合胃口吧，Tanya?
Listen to this.
听听这个。
"The world's most luxurious moisturiser
“世界最奢华的保湿霜
"contains flakes of 24carat gold
”内含24K镀金
"and extracts of donkey testicle."
“提取自驴睾丸之精华”
You're just jealous.
你不就是嫉妒我嘛。
At a thousand dollars a dollop.
价值千金
Tell you, that's the price you have to pay
告诉你，那是你应付的代价
if you wanna drink before 11:00 in the morning.
如果你想早上11点喝酒的话。
And we do.         We do.
是啊   是啊
May I help you?
有什么我能帮你们的？
Sure, we're here for the wedding.
当然，我们来参加婚礼的。
I'm Bill Anderson.
我是Bill Anderson。
I'm Bright, Harry Bright.
我是Bright, Harry Bright.
Sam Carmichael.
You are expecting us?
你在等我们吗？
Oh, my God. Yes!
噢，天哪。是的。
You're not Donna's daughter?
你该不是Donna的女儿吧？
I thought you looked familiar.
看着你就挺眼熟的。
Sofia.
It's Sophie.         Well, Sofia is the Greek.
是Sophie.          不过，希腊语就是Sofia.
Well, I'm named after a Sofia.
那也是，我就是以Sofia命名的。
I used to have a greataunt living on the mainland named Sofia.
以前我有个叫Sofia的曾姨妈住在大陆.
Would you mind if we see our rooms before we see your mother?
你介意我们在去见你母亲之前先看看我们的房间吗？
Sure.
好的很。
It's just that I'd quite like to freshen up before the big reunion.
我只想在破镜重圆之前调整到最佳状态。
No! No! I mean, yes,
不行！不行！我是说，可以，
but come this way.
但得走这边。
Come on!
来啊！
Oh, my God!
天！
I got a crack in my courtyard. I gotta go fix it.
院子里有个裂缝。我得补好它。
Hey, listen, Donna? Donna.
喂，听着，Donna? Donna.
Sit down!
坐下！
She won't let me go!         I know...
她不让我走！   我知道。。。
I know you're going to make a fortune with web's...
我知道你能靠着那个谁谁的。。。
"With web's..."         With Sky's site.
“那个谁来着”           Sky的网站。
I know you're gonna make a fortune with
我知道你能赚个盆满钵满
Sky's website, but...         It's good.
靠Sky的网站，但是。。。  没错。
Are you gonna be okay until then?
你能撑到那天吗？
I think Tanya is offering to pawn her bling.
看样子Tanya想要典当她的首饰了。
No, seriously, Donna...
不，我很认真，Donna...
Do you need a loan?         No, sweet.
你要贷款吗？   不，可人儿。
Oh, God, I'm just whining, you know me.
天，我只是抱怨而已，你了解我这人。
I don't need to be taken care of.
我不想被人照顾。
Yeah, but are you being taken care of?
是吗，但你不是一直被人照顾着吗？
What do you mean?         Are you getting any?
你什么意思？              你就没有那个过？
Oh, you mean...
哦，你是指。。。
Down, boy, down, boy. No, it takes too much energy.
克制，坏小子，克制，坏小子。不，这很费精力。
Yeah. Just more plumbing to be maintained, isn't it?
耶。又多了个要维护的管道，是吧？
Oh, God, I'm so glad that whole part of my life is over.
噢，天，我真高兴我的性生活完全结束了。
You know, seriously.
真的，跟你们说。
I do not miss it at all.
我一点也不怀念。
Then it's just right here. Good.
就在这里了。
Where's Donna? Hey! Okay.
Donna人在哪里？ 喂！OK。
Up you go.
上去就是了。
You know,I don't want to seem ungrateful for the scenic tour,
听我说，我非常感激这次的观光之旅，
but might I be shown my room now?
但是能带我去我的房间了吗?
Well, don't hold your breath, Harry, but I think this is your room.
别憋气了，Harry，我想这就是你的房间。
Can we see Donna now?
现在我们能去见Donna了吧？
I sent the invites.
是我发的请柬。
My mom doesn't know anything.
我妈对此毫不知情。
Well, she's done so much for me, and she's always talking about you guys
她为了付出很多，她常把你们挂在嘴边。
and the good old days, and
还有旧时的美好时光，还有
I thought, what an amazing surprise for her
我想你们能来参加我的婚礼
that you are all gonna be at my wedding.
会给她喜上加喜的。
Hang on, Sophie.
打住，Sophie.
I can't be here.
我不能踏足这里。
The last time I saw your mother,
上次我看到你母亲的时候，
she said she never wanted to see me again.
她说过永远也不想再见到我了。
That was years ago. Please, it would mean a lot to me.
那是多少年前的事了啊，拜托，这对我来说意义重大。
Why?         Listen, I can see that you've been to a great deal of trouble.
为什么?   听我说，能看出来你现在麻烦大了。
Might I suggest that we all reconvene on your boat?
我提议我们全部回到你的船上去！
Good idea.         Nope.
好主意。            不成。
Why?         It's an adventure, Harry.
怎么？     这是次冒险，Harry.
It's good for you.
对你有好处。
Okay, when I sent the invites,
OK,我送请柬的时候，
it was a long shot that you'd even reply.
我以为你们根本就不会回复我呢。
And now you've come all this way for a wedding.
哪知道你们跋山涉水来参加我的婚礼。
Surely there must have been some special reason for you to be here.
对你们来说这肯定有些特殊的原因。
Like some siren call, maybe?
像是海妖的召唤，也许吧？
You're a little minx, you know that? You're just like your mother.
你这丫头真够狡猾的，你知道吗？就像你母亲一样。
I'm glad my boys haven't met you. They'd never recover.
真高兴我的儿子们没碰到你。他们会无可救药的。
You have sons?         Yes, two.
你有儿子？         是啊，两个。
And someday, I'd like to bring them here.
什么时候，我也许会带他们来这儿。
Like you used to bring my mother?
就好象你过去带我母亲来这里？
No.         It's Donna.
不行。  是Donna。
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. Listen, listen, she can't know.
不行，不行，听我说，听我说，不能让她知道。
I'm going to go. Please stay.
我得走了。请别出去。
Promise me that you'll not tell anybody that I invited you.
答应我你们不会告诉任何人是我请你们来的。
Okay? Promise?
OK?答应我吧？
You got it, baby.         It's a promise.
我保证，宝贝。   我答应你。
I might regret it, but okay.         Okay.
我也许会后悔，但好吧。  OK.
There wouldn't, by any chance, happen to be a trouser press on the island, would there?
在这个岛上，你说这儿会不会有可能碰巧有一个熨斗呢？
Harry?
Bill?
* MAMMA MIA *
I was cheated by you
我被你欺骗了
And I think you know when
你应该知道是什么时候吧
So I made up my mind
所以我下定决心
It must come to an end
这该结束了
Look at me now
看看我吧
Will I ever learn?
我怎么就不开窍？
I don't know how
我不知道怎么回事
But I suddenly lose control
但我突然失控
There's a fire within my soul
在我心中有团火
Just one look and I can hear a bell ring
只看一眼我就能听到一声铃响
One more look and I forget everything
再看一眼我就会忘乎所以
Mamma mia Here I go again
妈妈咪呀感觉又来了
My, my How can I resist you?
我要怎样才能抵抗你呢？
Mamma mia Does it show again?
妈妈咪呀 又出现了吗？
My, my Just how much I've missed you
我有多么想念你呀
Yes, I've been brokenhearted
是啊，我曾经伤透了心
Blue since the day we parted
自分开那天起一直郁闷
Why, why did I ever let you go?
为什么会眼睁睁放你走？
Mamma mia Now I really know
妈妈咪呀我现在知道了
My, my I should not have let you go
我不该错放你的手
I was angry and sad When I knew we were through
当我知道我们完了的时候我很生气
I can't count all the times
我都数不清
I have cried over you
为了你我哭了多少次
Look at me now Will I ever learn?
看看我吧，我怎么就不开窍？
I don't know how
我不知怎么
But I suddenly lose control
突然就失控了
There's a fire within my soul
在我心中有团火
Just one look and I can hear a bell ring
只看一眼我就能听到一声铃响
One more look and I forget everything
再看一眼我就会忘乎所以
Mamma mia Here I go again
妈妈咪呀感觉又来了
My, my How can I resist you?
我要怎样才能抵抗你呢？
Mamma mia Does it show again?
妈妈咪呀 又出现了吗？
My, my Just how much I've missed you
我有多么想念你呀
Yes, I've been brokenhearted Blue since the day we parted
是啊，我曾经伤透了心 自分开那天起一直郁闷
Why, why did I ever let you go?
为什么会眼睁睁放你走？
Mamma mia Now I really know
妈妈咪呀我现在知道了
My, my I should not have let you go
我不该错放你的手
You always knew how to make an entrance.
你的入场总是那么别出心裁
I'd better be dreaming. You'd better not be here.
我最好是在做梦。你们最好不在这里。
You want me to pinch you, Donna?
你要我掐你吗，Donna?
No! You keep your hands to yourself, Bill Anderson.
不要！你掐自己吧，Bill Anderson.
You probably don't recognise me, do you?
你很可能认不出我来了吧？
Harry! It is you!
Harry!是你啊！
I probably changed a bit, but you certainly haven't.
我肯能有些改变了，但你明显没有。
Why are you here? What are you doing here?
你们为什么会来这里？到底要做什么啊！
I'm writing a travel piece.
我在写游记。
I'm here on a spontaneous holiday.
我自发地来这度假的。
I just dropped in to say hi.
我只是顺路过来跟你说hi的。
Okay. What is this?
OK.这到底怎么回事？
It's one of those serendipitous moments in life when three complete strangers
三个完全陌生的人能想到一块儿，
share a common thought.
只是英雄所见略同而已啦。
Strangers?
陌生人？
You don't know each other?
你们彼此不认识吗？
That's generally the definition.
陌生人的大意就是如此。
Okay, good, but who... Why are you here?
OK，good，但是谁。。为什么你们会在这儿？
Who said that you could stay up in my old goathouse?
谁跟你们说你们可以住在我的旧羊舍的
Didn't catch the name.Greek lady.
不记得名字了。希腊女士。
Well, she spoke Greek.
嗯，她说的希腊语。
Or maybe she said we couldn't stay in the old goathouse.
也许她说的是我们不能住在旧羊舍。
Yeah, maybe that was it, in Greek.
耶，有肯能，用希腊语说的就是了。
Yeah, that's it, that's it. You can't stay here because
那就对了。你们不能住这里 因为
I'm closed and I'm full.
我这歇业了而且爆满。
And I'm busy, I'm really... I have a wedding, my...
而且我很忙，我真的。。。我要举办一个婚礼，我的。。。
Local girl's getting married...
当地一个女孩要出嫁了。。。
Donna. Donna, don't worry about us.
Donna. Donna, 别为我们操心了。
Bill here is used to roughing it.
Bill来这是因为习惯了风雨。
And Harry here...         I'm spontaneous.
Harry在这。。。  我是自发而来的。
Spontaneous.
自发的
What about you?
那你呢？
Just wanted to see the island.
只是想来看看这座岛。
You know what it meant to me.
你知道它对我意味著什么。
Okay, I'm gonna arrange for a boat
好吧，我要去准备一条船
to take you all back to the mainland.
安排你们回大陆去。
I have a boat, Donna.         You have a boat?
我有船，Donna.        你有船？
Good, get on it,
好，快上船吧。
and anchors away.
然后扬帆离开。
Hey, Donna...         Away, away.
等下，Donna。。。 快走，快走。
It's good to see you.
能见到你真好。
Now, baby, this should tickle your taste buds.
宝贝，这杯肯定能触动你的味蕾。
Down, big fella. I'm old enough to be your mother.
得了吧，大小子。我的年纪都能做你母亲了。
Grandmother.
祖母。
Where's Sophie?
Sophie在哪？
I think she went down to the beach.         What's up?
我想她在海滩吧。          出什么事了？
Donna?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
不好意思啊。
Talk to her.
跟她说话啊。
Chiquitita, tell me what's wrong
Chiquitita, 告诉我怎么了
Oh, me.
噢，我。
I have never seen such sorrow
在你眼中我从未见到如此的悲伤
In your eyes And the wedding is tomorrow
明天就要举行婚礼了
How I hate to see you like this
我很不想看到你这样
There is no way you can deny it
你没有办法反悔了
I can see That you're oh, so sad So quiet
我知道你很悲伤很沉默
Chiquitita, tell me the truth
Chiquitita,实话个那我说吧
I'm a shoulder you can cry on
你哭的时候可以靠在我的肩膀
Your best friend,I'm the one you must rely on
你最好的朋友，你必须依赖的那个人就是我
You were always sure of yourself
你总是自信满满
Now I see you've broken a feather
我看到你折了翅
I hope we can patch it up Together
我希望我们能帮你早日康复
Chiquitita, you and I know
Chiquitita,你跟我都知道
How the heartaches come and they go
心痛只是暂时
And the scars, they're leaving
伤疤，也会消失
You'll be dancing once again And the pain will end
你终将又能起舞，痛苦也会结束
You will have no time for grieving
你将没有时间悲伤
Chiquitita, you and I cry
Chiquitita,你跟我一起哭泣
But the sun is still in the sky And shining above you
太阳依旧在你头顶的天空照耀
Let me hear you sing once more
就让我再次听到你的歌声吧
Like you did before Sing a new song, Chiquitita
像以前一样唱首新歌，
Try once more Like I did before
跟我以前一样在尝试一次吧
Sing a new song
唱首新歌
It's her dad.         Whose dad?
是她爸。  谁的爸?
Sophie's dad.
Sophie她爸
Remember how I said it was Sam? Sam the architect,
记得我说过是Sam吗？那个建筑师，
who had to go home to get married?
回家成亲的那个？
I'm not sure that it was him,
我不能肯定是他，
because there were two other guys around the same time.
因为同时我还和其他两个人。
Donna Sheridan. You shady lady.
Donna Sheridan.你这个荡妇。
Why didn't you tell us?
你之前为什么不告诉我们?
Well, I never knew that I would ever, ever have to.
那是因为我以后再也不会。
I never imagined I'd see all three of them
我没想到会同时看到他们
in my old goathouse
在我的旧羊舍里。
the day before my daughter's wedding!
就在我女儿婚礼的前一天！
The old goathouse?
旧羊舍？
No! No! Wait!
不要去！不要去！站住！
Shoot!
shiT!
Rosie! Tanya!
Wait a minute! Don't let them hear you!
等下！别让他们听到了啊！
There's no one here.         Are you sure?
这里没人啊。  你肯定吗？
Of course I'm sure!
我当然肯定啦！
Do you think I would forget my daughter's dads?
你以为我会忘记我女儿他爹们吗？
They were all here. Sam Carmichael,
他们刚才都在。Sam Carmichael,
Bill Anderson and Harry "Head Banger."
Bill Anderson and Harry "头锥男"
Harry "Head Banger."
Harry "头锥男"
They must've gone back to their boat.
他们肯定回自己船上去了。
I hope they run aground and drown.
我希望他们都淹死。
What are they doing here?
他们来这做什么啊?
It's like some hideous trick of fate.
总像是天意弄人啊。
It's very Greek.
真是入乡随俗。
Do they know about Sophie?
他们知道Sophie的事吗？
What are they, psychic?
你以为他们是谁啊，巫师吗？
No! I've never told a soul.
不！我可没跟鬼说过。
Oh, Donna, keeping it to yourself all these years.
噢，Donna，你都憋在心里这么多年了啊。
It doesn't matter about me.
对我没什么影响啦。
The only thing that matters is that Sophie never finds out.
要紧的是不能让Sophie知道这件事。
Well, maybe she would be cool with it.
也许她会很平静呢。
"Cool with it"?
平静？
You don't know my daughter. This would be like a bombshell.
你们不了解我女儿。这对她来说简直就是晴天霹雳。
Donna, they've gone!
Donna，他们都走了！
I don't know that.
那我就不知道了。
I don't know where they are. I don't know why they're here.
我不知道他们现在在哪。我不知道他们为什么会在这。
And I have brought this all on myself
而且我一直守口如瓶
because I was a stupid, reckless little slut!
就因为我是个愚蠢的，冒失的小淫妇！
Don't you sound like your mother?
你不觉得你的口气好像你母亲吗？
I do not!         Yes, you so do!
哪有！  没错，你绝对像！
You do, it's Catholic guilt!
你有，你犯了天主教的罪！
You've been living like a nun.
你过着修女般禁欲的生活。
Yeah, whatever happened to our Donna?
对，不管我们的Donna会有什么报应
Life and soul of the party,
聚会的灵魂人物，
el rock chick supremo?
I grew up.         Well, then, grow back down again.
我长大了。  那就再长回去啊。
Screw them if they can't take a joke.
要是他们开不起玩笑的话就甩了他们。
* DANCING QUEEN *
You can dance You can jive
你能跳舞 你能摇摆
Having the time of your life
享受你的风华正茂
See that girl Watch that scene
看那女孩 望着这场面
Dig in the dancing queen
摇摆皇后驾到
Friday night and the lights are low
礼拜五晚上灯光昏暗
Looking out for a place to go
四处寻找
Where they play the right music Getting in the swing
放着合意舞曲的地方 融入摇摆的人群
You come to look for a king
你来这找个国王
Anybody could be that guy
谁都可能是命中注定的那位
Night is young and the music's high
夜未央 舞正劲
With a bit of rock music Everything is fine
只要摇滚 万事如意
You're in the mood for a dance
你正有摇摆的冲动
And when you get the chance
当你抓住机会
You are the dancing queen
你就是摇摆皇后
Young and sweet Only seventeen
年轻貌美正十七
Dancing queen
摇摆皇后
Feel the beat from the tambourine
感受着节奏
Oh, yeah
You can dance You can jive
你能跳舞 你能摇摆
Having the time of your life
享受你的风华正茂
See that girl Watch that scene
看那女孩 望着这场面
Dig in the dancing queen
摇摆皇后驾到
You're a teaser You turn them on
你这个尤物 你让他们欲火中烧
Leave them burning And then you're gone
欲火中烧 一走了之
Looking out for another Anyone will do
然后继续狩猎 来者不拒
You're in the mood for a dance
你正有摇摆的冲动
And when you get the chance
当你抓住机会
You are the dancing queen
你就是摇摆皇后
Young and sweet Only seventeen
年轻貌美正十七
Dancing queen Feel the beat from the tambourine
感受着节奏
Oh, yeah
You can dance You can jive
你能跳舞 你能摇摆
Having the time of your life
享受你的风华正茂
See that girl Watch that scene
看那女孩 望着这场面
Dig in the dancing queen
摇摆皇后驾到
You can dance You can jive
你能跳舞 你能摇摆
Having the time of your life
享受你的风华正茂
See that girl
看那女孩
Watch that scene
望着这场面
Dig in the dancing queen
摇摆皇后驾到
Wait, wait. Wait! Hey, don't leave.
等等，等等！喂，别走啊。
Whoa, Sophie.
哇噢，Sophie.
We're gonna sail around the island. You wanna come?
我们绕岛航行。你想去吗？
You promised you'd come to my wedding.
你们答应我要参加我的婚礼的。
Yes, well, your mother ejected us from the goathouse.
对啊，可是你母亲把我们赶了出来。
She thought we'd better get out of her hair.
她想让我们别给她添麻烦。
Donna freaked out when she saw us.
Donna看到我们的时候惊慌失措。
What's all that about?         No.
那到底是怎么回事？  不是这样的。
She's just not even thinking straight. She's so stressed about the wedding.
她还没有想通啦。她太紧张明天的婚礼了。
You know, but she's got no idea that you're her lovely surprise.
她还不知道你们就是她可爱的惊喜啊。
She'll be so happy tomorrow.         You think so?
她明天就会很开心了。   你是这么想的吗？
You took Mom's guitar!
你拿了妈妈的吉他？
No, no. I borrowed it. Look.
不，不。我借的。瞧。
No, where is it?
不，在哪呢？
D.S.
Donna Sheridan.
And H.B.
Head Banger.
Head Banger?
I bought her this. It cost me ten quid
我买给她的。花了我10英镑。
plus my Johnny Rotten Tshirt.
还有我的Johnny Rotten T恤。
Your mother knew quite a rebel.
你母亲认识的是一个相当反叛的人。
I was studying in Paris when I met her.
碰到她的时候我正在巴黎进修。
I hopped on a train and followed her to Greece,
我跳上了火车跟踪她来到希腊，
quite spontaneously.
相当的自发。
I can still recall
我仍然记得
Our last summer
我们最后的夏天
I still see it all
历历在目
Walks along the Seine
散步在塞因河畔
Laughing in the rain
在雨中欢笑
Our last summer
我们最后的夏天
Memories that remain
记忆尚存
We made our way along the river
沿河漫步
And we sat down in the grass
绿野中促膝
By the Eiffel Tower
埃菲尔铁塔旁
I was so happy we had met
我们的相遇让我欢喜
It was the age of no regret
没有遗憾的年纪
Oh, yes
Those crazy years, that was the time
那个疯狂的年代，那是个
Of the flower power
鲜花当道的的时代
But underneath we had a fear of flying
心中我们对飞逝的时间
Of growing old A fear of slowly dying
慢慢死去有所顾忌
We took a chance
我们抓住机会
Like we were dancing our last dance
好像我们在跳最后一次舞
I can still recall Our last summer
我还记得我们最后的夏天
I still see it all
历历在目
In the tourist jam round the Notre Dame
在游人如织的Notre Dame
Our last summer Walking hand in hand
我们最后的夏天手牵着手
Paris restaurants
巴黎饭店
Our last summer Morning croissants
我们最后的夏天 早晨的新月
Living for the day Worries far away
今朝有酒今朝醉
Our last summer
我们最后的夏天
We could laugh and play
我们可以嬉笑
And now you're working in a bank
然而现在你在银行工作
A family man, a football fan
有了家室，足球迷
And your name is Harry
你的名字是Harry
How dull it seems
多么乏味啊
Are you the hero of my dreams?
你就是我梦中的英雄吗？
Sophie!
Sophie!         Please, I have to go,
我得走了。
but please come tomorrow, okay?         Absolutely.
请明天一定要来啊。  那是当然了。
We'll be there.         It's a promise.
我们回去的。  这是个承诺。
Walks along the Seine
散步在塞因河畔
Laughing in the rain
在雨中欢笑
Our last summer
我们最后的夏天
Memories that remain
记忆尚存
Sky!
Where've you been?
你去哪里了？
People have been arriving all afternoon. No one's seen you.
客人整个下午不断抵达。没有人看到过你。
I'm sorry, I was around the island, I just...
对不起，我在岛上转了转，我只是
I just lost track of time.
忘记了时间。
Where're you going?         It's my stag do.
你要去哪里？  参加雄鹿会（只限男子参加的聚会, 尤指为准新郎举行的）
My last night of freedom.
我自由身的最后一晚。
Which is how some people might see it, but for me,
某些人是这么认为的，但对我来说，
it's the last night before the greatest adventure of my life.
这是我这辈子最伟大冒险的前夜。
You know how I said I wanted to find my father?
你记得我说过要找到我的父亲吗？
Soph, we've been over this a million times.
Soph，我们都谈这个无数次了。
You don't need a father, you have a family.
你不需要一个父亲，你有一个家庭。
And you'll never leave me, right?
你永远也不会离开我吗？
Are you kidding? You have turned my world upside down.
你开什么玩笑？是你颠覆了我的世界啊。
* LAY ALL YOUR LOVE ON ME *
把所有你的爱投注在我身上吧
I wasn't jealous before we met
在遇到你之前我还不会嫉妒
Now every man that I see is a potential threat
现在我见到的每一个男人都是潜在的威胁
And I'm possessive It isn't nice
我令人不快的占有欲
You've heard me saying that smoking was my only vice
以前我跟你说吸烟是我唯一的恶习
But now it isn't true
现在这不再是了
Now everything is new
现在情况不同了
And all I've learned has overturned
我已知的一切都被颠覆
I beg of you
我乞求你
Don't go wasting your emotion
别再浪费你的感情了
Lay all your love on me
把所有你的爱倾注在我身上吧
It was like shooting a sitting duck
就像是在射一只无力招架的鸭子
A little small talk, a smile and
寥寥数语，一个微笑
baby, I was stuck
宝贝，我就无力动弹
I still don't know what you've done with me
我还不知道你对我做了什么
A grownup woman should never fall so easily
成熟女人不应如此轻易坠入爱河
I feel a kind of fear
我心慌
When I don't have you near
当你不在我身旁
Unsatisfied, I skip my pride
欲求不满，我抛弃自尊
I beg you, dear
我乞求你，亲！
Don't go wasting your emotion
别再浪费你的情感了
Lay all your love on me
把所有你的爱倾注在我身上吧
Don't go sharing your devotion
不要再把你的挚爱分享
Lay all your love on me
把所有你的爱倾注在我身上吧
Don't go wasting your emotion
别再浪费你的情感了
Lay all your love on me
把所有你的爱倾注在我身上吧
Don't go sharing your devotion
不要再把你的挚爱分享
Lay all your love on me
把所有你的爱倾注在我身上吧
Ladies and no gentlemen,
女士们，没有先生们
presenting, for one night and one night only...
接下来，请欣赏  一夜，只要一夜
Because that's all we've got breath for.
因为那是我们没咽气的原因。
Speak for yourself, you old bat!
别代表我们，你这老女人！
The world's first girl power band,
世界上第一支女权乐队，
Donna and the Dynamos.
Donna and the Dynamos。
Super Trouper
超级明星
Lights are gonna find me
灯光将会把我照耀
But I won't feel blue
但我不灰心
Like I always do
像往常的我
'Cause somewhere in the crowd, there's you
因为在人群的某处，有你
* SUPER TROUPER *
* 超级明星*
I was sick and tired of everything
世事让我烦心
When I called you last night from Glasgow
当我昨晚在格拉斯哥给你打电话时
All I do is eat and sleep and sing
我整天就是吃睡唱歌
Wishing every show was the last show
希望每场秀都是最后一秀
So imagine I was glad to hear you're coming
幻想着我高兴的听说你要来了
Suddenly I feel all right
突然我感觉好多了
And suddenly it's gonna be
突然这变得
And it's gonna be so different when I'm on the stage tonight
这变得大不同 当我今晚站在台前
Tonight the Super Trouper Lights are gonna find me
今晚我就是超级明星  灯光将把我照耀
Our song.         Your song?
我们俩儿的歌。  你的歌？
It's my song.
是我的歌才对。
Smiling, having fun
笑啊，开心啊
Feeling like a number one
感觉好像世界第一
Tonight the Super Trouper
今晚我就是超级明星
Beams are gonna blind me
光柱使我失明
But I won't feel blue
但我不会灰心
Like I always do
像往常的我
'Cause somewhere in the crowd, there's you
因为在人群的某处，有你
So I'll be there when you arrive
当你到来的时候我将为你守候
The sight of you will prove to me I'm still alive
你的目光所及将会证明我仍然活着
And when you take me in your arms
当你拥我入怀
And hold me tight
抱紧我
I know it's gonna mean so much tonight
我知道今晚意义非凡
Tonight the Super Trouper Lights are gonna find me
今晚我就是超级明星 灯光将会把我照耀
Shining like the sun
像太阳般发光
Look, look, look, look, look.
快看 快看 快看那
Smiling, having fun
笑啊，开心啊
Feeling like a number one
感觉好像世界第一
Tonight the Super Trouper
今晚我就是超级明星
Beams are gonna blind me
光柱使我失明
But I won't feel blue
但我不会灰心
Like I always do
像往常的我
'Cause somewhere in the crowd, there's you
因为在人群的里面，有你
Super Trouper lights Are gonna find me
超级明星 灯光将会把我照耀
I can't believe you!
难以置信！
Excuse me! Hello.
不好意思！
This is a hen party. Women only!
这是一场女性聚会。仅限女性！
Thank you.         Okay.
谢谢，  OK。
Why are they here, then,
他们为什么会在这里
if it's not to ruin Sophie's wedding?
如果不是来破坏Sophie的婚礼？
But I thought you weren't so keen on this wedding.
我还以为你不会这么热衷这场婚礼的。
I don't want them spoiling it.
我不想让他们你毁了它。
They have no right to turn up like this.
他们没有权利像这样冒出来。
What have they ever done for their daughter?
他们可曾为自己的女儿做过什么？
Donna, Donna, they didn't know she existed.
Donna, Donna, 他们不知道她的存在啊。
Well, they didn't need to know, did they?
哦，他们不需要知道，对吧？
I've done a great job with Soph, all by myself,
我总算把Soph抚养成人，全靠我一个人，
and I won't be muscled out by an ejaculation!
我才不会被那些只会射精的家伙扳倒呢！
* GIMME! GIMME! GIMME! *
Is there a man out there?
那边坐的是个男人吗？
Someone to hear my prayer?
有人愿意听我祷告吗？
Gimme! Gimme! Gimme! A man after midnight
给我！给我！给我！午夜以后给我一个男人
Won't somebody help me Chase the shadows away
有人愿意帮我赶走那些影子
Gimme! Gimme! Gimme! A man after midnight
给我！给我！给我！午夜以后给我一个男人
Hi.         Hi.
I think I should explain to Donna that I come in peace.
我想我该向Donna解释一下我来这儿不是为了兴风作浪
Oh, no, really. You should wait until she has a few drinks in her first.
噢，不，真的。你应该等到她先喝几杯再说。
Really.         Good idea. Good idea.
真的。              好主意。好主意。
What you drew on the boat...
你在船上画的这个。。。
This is good. This is really good.
画得很好。画得真的很好。
Why don't you pursue this? You have a real talent here.
你为什么不去进修呢？你在这方面很有天赋。
I have enough to do here.
我在这儿有忙不完的事要做呢。
Is that really your dream?
那真的是你的梦想吗？
Running the villa with Donna?
和Donna一起经营这家度假村？
She just can't do it by herself.
她一个人做不下去的。
Do you know,
告诉你吧，
I drew this whole place up
我花了一个晚上在菜单的背面
on the back of a menu one night.
把这个地方都画了出来
I always dreamt I'd come back here.
我一直做梦都想回到这里。
What kept you?
那你怎么不来？
What's your mother said about me?
你妈都跟你说了我什么吗？
She never mentioned you.         Sophie?
她从来就没提起过你。
What am I doing here?
那我还在这里做什么？
Some air in here.
上来透个气吧。
Somebody up there has got it in for me.
上面一定有人帮我的。
I bet it's my mother.
我打赌是我的母亲。
Oh, and wasn't she a ray of sunshine.
噢，她不会是一束阳光吧。
I'm gonna go get them out of here.
我要出去把他们赶出这里。
You go in there guns loaded, there's gonna be questions.
你全副武装的进去，绝对会出问题的。
Help me out of these boots.
帮我把这些靴子脱掉啊。
All that fricking yoga's made my feet bigger.
讨厌的瑜伽把我的脚搞大了。
Now, listen. Listen, what we're gonna do is,
听着。听着，我们这样做吧，
we'll get them plastered tonight,
今晚把他们都灌醉，
and then tomorrow, Tanya and I will take them fishing.
然后明天，Tanya和我就带他们去钓鱼。
Fishing? Oh, please.
钓鱼？噢，饶了我吧。
What do you suggest we do with three men?
那你建议我们该跟三个男人做什么？
Well, then, now, that takes me back.
好了，这下把我拉回来了。
Gimme! Gimme! Gimme!
给我！给我！给我！
A man after midnight
午夜给我一个男人
Take me through the darkness To the break of the day
伴我度过黑夜直到黎明
Hello.         You okay?
哈罗。  你还好吗？
I'm fine.
还好。
Fancy Donna having a grownup daughter!
可爱的Donna有了个长大成人的女儿！
Do you have any children, Harry?         Well, I have the dogs, Lucy and Kipper.
你有孩子吗，Harry?               呃，我有两只狗，LUCY和Kipper。
That's the extent of my relationships.
那就是我所有的亲缘关系了。
I'd have loved a daughter. I'd have spoiled her rotten.
有个女儿我会很高兴的。我一定会把她宠坏的。
Is your father here?         I don't know.
你的父亲在这里吗？  我不知道。
I don't know who my father is.
我不知道谁是我的父亲。
Is there a man out there?
这里有男人吗？
Someone to hear my prayer?
有人听到我的祈祷了吗？
This is fantastic!
真是棒极了！
How on earth did Donna get money to buy this place?
Donna到底是从哪弄来的钱买的这个地方？
She was left some money by the old lady
我小时候，她曾经照顾过的一个老夫人
she looked after when I was little.
给她留下了一些钱
Sofia, that I'm named after.
Sofia，我的名字就是以她命名的。
My greataunt Sofia?
我的曾姨妈Sofia?
I guess.
我猜是。
I always heard her money was left to family.
我一直听说她把钱留给了家人。
How old are you?         I'm 20.
你多大了？     20.
Will you excuse me a minute?
失陪了
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Bill! Bill, wait.
等一下。
Why did your greataunt leave my mother money?
为什么你的曾姨妈会把钱留给我妈呢？
I don't know!
我不晓得！
All my life, there's been this huge unanswered question,
我这么大了，这个问题从来就没人告诉我为什么，
and I don't want any more secrecy!
我再也不要被继续保密下去了！
What do you want from me?
你想从我这儿得到什么？
Bill, please!
Bill, 求你了！
Are you my father?
你是我父亲吗？
Yes. I think so.
是的，我想是。
Yes.
You know what comes next?
你知道我要告诉你什么吗？
Oh, you're not going to tell me that you have a twin sister, are you?
噢，你不会要告诉我你还有个双胞胎姐姐吧？
Will you give me away tomorrow?
明天你能把我托付给新郎吗？
Give you away?         No! Our secret until the wedding.
把你托付给新郎？             不！婚礼之前我们的秘密。
Cute.
可爱极了
Oh, God.
噢，上帝。
Okay.
* VOULEZVOUS *
People everywhere
到处都是人
A sense of expectation hanging in the air
空气中弥漫着期待
Giving out a spark
闪出一个火花
Across the room your eyes are glowing in the dark
你的眼睛在漆黑的屋子里发着光
And here we go again We know the start, we know the end
我们又来了 我们知道序幕，我们知道结局
Masters of the scene
剧场的主宰
We've done it all before And now we're back to get some more
我们又要故技重施
You know what I mean
你知道我说到做到
Voulezvous
Take it now or leave it
接受与否
Now is all we get
珍惜现在
Nothing promised, no regrets
没有承诺，没有遗憾
Voulezvous
Ain't no big decision
又不是什么大决定
You know what to do
你知道该怎么做
La question c'est voulezvous Voulezvous
Go dance with Mom!
跟妈妈跳舞去！
Sophie, come here.
Sophie, 过来。
I know why I'm here.
我知道我为什么来这了。
Why didn't Donna tell me?
为什么Donna没有告诉我？
How long have you known I'm your father?
你知道我是你父亲多久了？
What? Not long at all.
什么？我之前一直就不知道。
Sam, listen to me. My mom doesn't know that I know.
Sam,听我说。我妈不知道我知道了。
So can we wait until after my wedding?
所以我们能等到我的婚礼之后吗？
Who's giving you away tomorrow?         Nobody.
明天谁会把你托付给新郎？      没人啊。
Wrong. I am.
错。我会。
Our secret till then.
到那之前是我们的秘密。
Voulezvous
Take it now or leave it
接受与否
Now is all we get
珍惜现在
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
I can't breathe.
我无法呼吸了。
Voulezvous
Ain't no big decision
又不是什么大决定
You know what to do
你知道该怎么做
La question c'est voulezvous Voulezvous
Oh, my God! I'm your father!
噢，我的天啊！我是你父亲！
Harry!
Now, that's why you sent me the invite.
现在我知道你为什么要邀请我来了。
You wanted your old dad to walk you down the aisle.
你想你的老爹陪你走完教堂那条走廊。
Well, I won't let you down. I'll be there.
我不会让你失望的。我一定到场。
Voulezvous
Take it now or leave it
接受与否
Now is all we get
珍惜现在
Nothing promised, no regrets
没有承诺，没有遗憾
Voulezvous
Ain't no big decision
又不是什么大决定
You know what to do
你知道该怎么做
La question c'est voulezvous
For the wedding.        Upside down.
为了婚礼。   上下颠倒。
Fancy Donna having a...
可爱的Donna有个
I'm your...
我是你的
Who's giving you...
谁会把你托。。
Sophie! Soph!
Stand back, everybody. Give her some space.
退后，大家。给她腾个地方
Soph... Baby!
Soph。。。宝贝！
Come on, Mother, rise and shine.
行了，母亲，起来晒晒吧。
I was tossing and turning all night.
我辗转反侧一整夜。
Those three guys are still loose on this island.
那三个家伙现在仍然在这岛上游荡。
We got to do something.
我们得做点什么。
Donna! Donna! Donna! Donna. It's all under control.
Donna! Donna! Donna! Donna. 一切尽在掌握。
I have been tossing and turning all night.
我辗转反侧一整夜。
I've got three dads coming to my wedding,
我有三个爹参加我的婚礼，
and I have to tell two of them they're surplus. Only, which two?
而且我得告诉他们其中的两个他们是多余的。问题是，哪两个？
It's all under control.
一切尽在掌握。
I'm taking Bill and Sam fishing...
我要带Bill和Sam去钓鱼。。。
We're each gonna go off. We're gonna grab a man,
我们每个人都去抓一个男人，
interrogate him, swap notes and decide.
审问他，交换口供然后决定。
And Harry's talked Tanya into water sports.
然后Harry说服Tanya去搞水上运动。
Oh, God. Nurse, donkey testicles, quickly!
噢，天。护士，快拿驴蛋来！
No, after you. Please.         No. No. Go ahead.
不，你先请。  不。不。你先。
No, no, no, no, you first.
不，不，不，你先。
I want to get something off my chest.         Me, too.
我有些事不吐不快。           我也是。
Last night, I discovered something wonderful.
昨夜，我发现一些非常好的事情。
It was a wakeup call, a way to look at myself and
像是个闹钟，帮助我看清自己 让我知道
what I really want out of life.
我这辈子里到底想要些什么。
Last night? You didn't know?
昨晚？你还不知道？
You didn't even suspect that you were...
你甚至都没有怀疑你是。。。
Well, no. Of course not. That's always been a secret.
不。当然不。这一直都是个秘密。
And now we... Say it out loud.
现在我们。。。大声说出来吧。
No! No! No! It's absolutely hushhush. I mean, for now.
不！不！不！绝对不能喧哗。我是说现在。
All will be revealed tonight.
今晚就会真相大白了。
Talking of revelations, last night...
说到秘密，昨晚。。。
You and the little lady? I think I know what's going on.
你和那个小妇人？我想我知道是怎么回事了。
No, you don't. You don't.         It's obvious.
不，你不知道。你不知道。   太假了吧。
I saw it from the moment you clapped eyes on each other.
看到你们两互相眨眼睛我就知道了。
You're kidding.
你在说笑。
I'm gonna level with you, Harry.
我得坦白跟你说，Harry.
I don't think I can do this.
我想我做不到。
Well, she's a wonderful girl,
没错，她是个非常好的女孩子，
but can I take her on in my life?
但是我能照顾好她吗？
Bill, where's your spontaneity?
Bill,你的自发性哪里去了？
It's this...
是这样的。。
This family, you know?         You don't have to marry her.
这个家庭，你懂吗？  你又不一定要娶她。
What?
什么？
Hey, right in time for breakfast.
嘿，正好赶上早餐。
We're serving up the works here.
我们正在忙着呢。
Think you just did.
我想也是。
Sunnyside up! Lox or ham?
向阳的朝上！熏鱼还是火腿？
I'll just...
我还是。。
I'm just gonna...
我还是先。。。
What a mess!
乱七八糟！
Hey!         What?
喂！    怎么了啊？
You okay?         Yeah. I'm fine. I'm fine.
你还好吧？      嗯。我很好。我很好。
Sophie.         What?
Sophie.   还有什么？
Last night, you and Sky... What's wrong?
昨晚，你跟SKY...  出什么事了？
Tell me. Tell me what's wrong.
告诉我。告诉我出什么事了。
I don't know what to do.         You know what to do.
我不知道该怎么做。          你知道该怎么做。
You don't have to do anything.
你什么事也不用做。
Not too late, I can still call off the wedding. Everybody will understand.
还不算太晚，我还可以取消婚礼。大家都会理解的。
Call... Call off the wedding?
取消婚礼
Isn't that what you want?         No.
你不想这样吗？          不。
No. No, that's what you want.
不。不，你才想这样。
No!Sophie!        Yes! God!
不！Sophie!       是的！天！
You just... You have no idea. You never had a wedding.
你根本。。。你不会知道。你从来就没有结过婚。
You never did the marriageandbabies thing.
你从来就没有结婚怀孕。
You just did the baby thing.
你直接怀了孕。
Well, good for you.         You know, I don't know why
嗯，算你走运。  告诉你，我不知道为什么
you're going off on me now! I really don't!         Because I...
你朝我发脾气！我真不知道！      因为我。。。
God! I love Sky, and I want to be with him!
我爱SKY,我想跟他在一起！
And I don't want my children growing up
我不想我的孩子们长大了
not knowing who their father is.
都不知道他们的父亲是谁。
Because it's just... It's crap!
因为这。。。简直就是胡闹！
Voulezvous
Stop, you're terrible.
打住，你唱的真恐怖。
Come on, man. What are you talking about?
什么啊，你们。你怎么能这么说呢？
Okay, okay, Sophie's gonna have an absolutely beautiful wedding, right?
OK,OK,Sophie会有个相当漂亮的婚礼，对不对？
You're supposed to be helping me.
你们本来应该帮我的。
You guys... He's got to get ready.
你们。。。他应该准备好了。
I see you kept my bagpipes.
我看到你保留了我的风笛。
They're supposed to ward off unwanted visitors.
我用它们来挡住不速之客。
Well, you don't need bagpipes to do that.
那么，你不需要风笛也能做到。
What are you doing here, Sam?
你来这干嘛，Sam?
This is our dream, remember?
这是我们的梦想，还记得吗？
Villa on the island?
在这岛上建个度假村？
Yeah. Well, this is my reality.
是，没错，这是我的现实。
Hard work and a crippling mortgage. Shoot!
忙不完的活和还不完的贷款。shiT!
And a hotel that's crumbling around me.
还有我周围摇摇欲坠的酒店。
Look, I'll help...
来，我可以帮。。。
No, that's all right, I can
不用，这还好，我还能
deal my own disasters.
应付我自己的灾难。
Why didn't you tell me it was Sophie getting married?
你为什么不告诉我是Sophie要结婚了？
Well, I didn't think it was any of your business.
那是因为我以为这不关你的事。
Why is she getting married? Settling down on the island?
她为什么要结婚？在这岛上定居吗？
I mean, if it was up to me, I'd be telling her to go get a life.
我是说，如果让我来说的话，我会告诉她去过其他的生活。
She's a bright kid.
她是个聪明的孩子。
I know. I know.
我知道。我知道。
But, you know, my daughter has a mind of her own.
但是，你知道的，我女儿有自己的想法。
Oh, yeah. I see that. I see that.
哦，是啊。我明白了。我明白了。
But she's so young.         I know.
但是她还年轻。         我知道。
I mean, does she know what she really wants?
我指的是，她知道自己真的想要什么吗？
You see, I think part of her just wants to let you know
你瞧，我以为她的一部分想法是想让你知道
that she isn't going to leave you alone here, on your own.
她不会把你一个人留在这里，无依无靠。
What do you mean?         Donna, look.
你什么意思啊？     Donna,瞧。
I have two grown children.
我有两个长大的孩子。
I know something about letting go.
我知道该何时放手。
If Sophie felt you were okay on your own,
如果Sophie觉得你可以无依无靠的话，
would she want something different for herself?
她难道就不想体验些许不同吗？
Okay, here's the thing.
OK，事情是这样的。
I love being on my own. I really do.
我喜欢无依无靠。我真的喜欢。
You know, every morning, I get up and I thank God
你知道，每个清晨，我醒来之后感谢上帝
that I don't have some middleaged, menopausal man
让我没有一些中年“绝经”了的男人
telling me how to run my life.
告诉我该如何经营我的生活。
You know, I'm free and I'm single.
你看到了，我很自由而且还是单身。
And it's great.
这样很好。
SOS
Where are those happy days?
那些快乐的自己哪里去了？
They seem so hard to find
它们似乎很难寻回了
I try to reach for you But you have closed your mind
我联系过你但你已经封闭了你的心窗
What ever happened to our love?
我们的爱到底出了什么事啊？
I wish I understood
我希望我能明白
It used to be so nice It used to be so good
它曾是那么令人愉悦 那么美好
So when you're near me, darling Can't you hear me?
当你我近在咫尺，打令你能听到我啊？
SOS
The love you gave me Nothing else can save me
除了你给我的爱其他一切都无法拯救我
SOS
When you're gone How can I even try to go on?
当你离开之后我怎么能在试着继续生活下去？
When you're gone, though I try How can I carry on?
当你离开之后 尽管我试着 我怎么能继续生活下去？
You seem so far away though you are standing near
尽管你站在我身旁你看起来仍是那么遥远
You made me feel alive but something died, I fear
我恐怕 你让我感觉还活着但某些东西已经死去
I really tried to make it out
我真的有试过理解
I wish I understood
我希望我能懂
What happened to our love? It used to be so good
我们的爱到底出了什么事啊？它曾是那么美好
So when you're near me, darling Can't you hear me?
当你我近在咫尺，打令你能听到我啊？
SOS
And the love you gave me Nothing else can save me
除了你给我的爱其他一切都无法拯救我
SOS
When you're gone
当你离开之后
How can I even try to go on?
我怎么能在试着继续生活下去？
When you're gone
当你离开之后
Though I try how can I carry on?
尽管我试着 我怎么能继续生活下去？
Donna must be tearing her hair out, doing this wedding on her own.
Donna都快把头发扯光了吧，无所依靠的筹备这场婚礼。
What would the father of the bride normally do?
新娘的父亲通常都会怎么做呢？
Pay. Though my dad drew the line at my third.
埋单。不过我爹在我第三次（婚礼）时划清了界限。
I see. Excuse me.
我知道了。失陪。
Harry?
Harry!
Tanya! Let's pick up where we left off last night.
Tanya!我们继续昨晚没有做完的事吧。
Last night never happened.
昨晚什么都没发生过。
I've drawn a veil over last night.
我已经忘得一干二净了。
Oh, my God. Look at the time. I've got work to do.
噢，我的天。时候不早了。我有工作要做。
Work?         A little repair and renovation.
工作? 一点修理和翻新。
Come on. You don't mess with a masterpiece.
别这样啊。你不要埋没了我这旷世奇才啊。
Oh, ignore him, Tanya, he's all mouth and no trousers.
噢，无视他把，Tanya,他油嘴滑舌还没有长裤。
Tanya can't ignore the chemistry between us.
Tanya无法无视我们之间的不可思议的情愫。
Little boys who play with fire get their fingers burned.
玩火的小孩通常会把自己的手烧到。
* DOES YOUR MOTHER KNOW *
* 你娘知道吗 *
You're so hot, teasing me
你很性感，勾起我欲望
So you're blue Well, I can't take a chance on a kid like you
你很下（风）流，抱歉，我还是不能和你这样的孩子玩火
It's something I couldn't do
这是我的原则
There's that look in your eyes
从你的眼神中
I can read in your face that your feelings are driving you wild
我能读到你内心正在抓狂
Oh, but, boy, you're only a child
噢，但，男孩，你还只是个孩子
Well, I can dance with you, honey If you think it's funny
好吧，我可以和你跳舞，甜心如果你认为这很有趣的话
But does your mother know that you're out?
但是你娘知道你出来了吗？
And I can chat with you, baby Flirt a little, maybe
我也可以和你聊聊，宝贝，调调情，也许
Does your mother know that you're out?
但是你娘知道你出来了吗？
Take it easy Take it easy. Better slow down, boy
放松些 放松些。最好慢慢来，男孩
That's no way to go Does your mother know?
还是没有办法  你娘知道吗？
Take it easy Take it easy. Try to cool it, boy
放松些 放松些。最好慢慢来，男孩
Play it nice and slow Does your mother know?
慢慢玩，你娘知道吗？
Come on, boy.
跳起来，男孩子们
I can see what you want
我看得出来你们想要什么
But you seem pretty young To be searching for that kind of fun
但是你们还不到寻找那种快感的年纪
So maybe I'm not the one
也许我还不是命中注定的那位
Now you're so cute I like your style
你是这么可爱 我喜欢你这种类型
And I know what you mean
我也知道你指的是什么了
When you give me a flash of that smile
当你给了我那种坏坏的笑容之后
But, boy, you're only a child
但是，男孩，你还只是个孩子
Well, I can dance with you, honey If you think it's funny
好吧，我可以和你跳舞，甜心如果你认为这很有趣的话
Does your mother know that you're out?
但是你娘知道你出来了吗？
And I can chat with you, baby Flirt a little, maybe
我也可以和你聊聊，宝贝，调调情，也许
Does your mother know that you're out?
但是你娘知道你出来了吗？
Well, I can dance with you, honey If you think it's funny
好吧，我可以和你跳舞，甜心如果你认为这很有趣的话
Does your mother know that you're out?
但是你娘知道你出来了吗？
And I can chat with you, baby Flirt a little, maybe
我也可以和你聊聊，宝贝，调调情，也许
Does your mother know that you're out?
你娘知道你出来了吗？
Does your mother know? Does your mother know that you're out?
你娘知道吗？你娘知道你出来了吗？
Boy down! Boy down!
不行咯！不行咯！
Yo, girls. We done good.
美眉们。我们干得好。
Yes, any colour. Doesn't matter.
什么颜色都行。没关系。
There's no plan, God knows there's no plan.
没有计划。上帝都知道没有计划。
It looks great, though.         Ella, Donna, where would you like this?
看起来还不错。           Donna,这个该放哪比较合适呢？
Carlos, get the meat out of the heat.
Carlos，把肉从火上拿下来。
Put a cover on that thing. That's beautiful. And tell... lone, help him get the...
找个东西盖在那东西上。那样就漂亮了。告诉Lone，帮他把。。。
Harry, what are you doing here?         Hello.
HarrY,你在这儿干嘛？              哈喽。
I just wanted to give you this.
我是来给你这个的。
I don't mean here, here.
我不是说这儿的这儿。
I mean, why are you on this island?
我的意识，你为什么会来这个岛？
What is this?
这是什么？
Now, I realised you'll have had to tighten your belt a bit over the years,
现在，我知道你这些年勒紧了裤腰带
bringing up Sophie on your own,
独自把Sophie抚养长大
and I just wanted to make a small contribution to the wedding.
我只想为这个婚礼做些小小的贡献。
I can't accept this. I can't...
我不能接受这个。我不能。。。
Harry, I can't.
HarrY，我不能。
No, you'll have to catch me first.
不，你得抓到我先。
Sky.         What's the matter?
SKY.  什么事？
You have to help me.         Why, what's happened?
你得帮帮我。 为啥，发生了什么事？
Baby?
宝贝？
Sophie!
Soph.
I've done something completely insane.
我做了一些非常不理智的事情。
All my dads are here for our wedding,
我所有的爹爹都来了参加我的婚礼。
and they all think they're giving me away.
并且他们都以为他们会把我托付个你。
All your what?
你所有的什么？
I read Mom's diary, and I have three possible fathers.
我读了妈妈的日记，知道了我又三个可能的父亲。
But how are they here now?
但是他们怎么会来这里的？
I invited them.
我邀请了他们。
I thought that I would know my dad right away,
我以为我会立马知道谁是我的爹，
but I didn't. I just...
但我没有，我只是
I have no idea. And now, my mom is gonna kill me,
我不知所措。现在我妈想杀了我，
and they're gonna hate me, and you...         Hold on. Hold on.
他们也会恨我的，连你。。。  等等。等等。
You invited these guys and you didn't tell me?
你邀请了这些家伙但你没有告诉我？
No, I thought you would try to stop me.
不，我以为你会阻止我的。
I know I messed up.         Sophie?
我知道我这么做不对。 SOphie?
Is that what this whole big white wedding is about?
这就是你要的那个盛大的白色婚礼的原因？
You finding your dad?        No. No!
跟你父亲破镜重圆？  不。不是！
I wanted to take a boat to the mainland with a couple of witnesses.
我想跟几个见证人搭艘船去大陆
And you insisted on this sodding circus
而你坚持要要搞这见鬼的把戏
so you could play Happy Families.
这样你就可以上演大团圆了。
It's about knowing who I am.
这都是为了知道我是谁。
And I wanted to get married knowing who I am.
我想要在我知道我是谁的情况下结婚
That doesn't come from finding your father,
找到你的父亲不能让你知道你是谁，
that comes from finding yourself.
找到你自己才能知道。
And the irony is, I was travelling to find myself.
讽刺的是，我旅行就是为了找到我自己。
I put everything on hold for you.
我为你暂停了一切
Because I loved you and I wanted what you wanted.
因为我爱你，我想拥有你想拥有的。
Now, I don't know.
现在，我不知道了。
You don't know if you love me?
你不知道你是否爱我？
Of course I love you. I just wish you'd told me.
我当然爱你了。我只祈盼你会告诉我。
Is everything okay?
没什么事吧？
Sophie, what's wrong?         Not now, Sam.
Sophie, 出什么事了？            不是现在，Sam.
Yes, yes, yes, now.
就是现在。
Because I'm supposed to be giving you away.
因为我是那个要把你托付给新郎的人。
And how can I when I know you're not really gonna be happy?
当我知道你不会真的幸福之后我怎么能把你托付出去？
I've heard all this from my mother, and I think she knows me better than you do.
这些我都听我妈说过了，我认为她比你更了解我。
I know. But I've done the big white wedding, and believe me,
我知道。但我结果这么一个大的白色婚礼，相信我，
it doesn't always end in "happy ever after."
它的结局不总是“永远幸福”
That is you. That's not me.
那是你。那不是我。
Okay? I love Sky more than anything in the world. And I...
OK?我爱SKY胜过这个世界上的任何人。我。。。
Did you feel that way before you got married?
你在你结婚之前有过这种感觉吗？
No.
没有。
Hey, aren't you supposed to be getting dressed?
喂，你不是应该去穿上婚纱了吗？
Where's Ali and Lisa? I thought they were going to help you.
Ali和Lisa在哪呢？我以为她们会帮你的。
Will you help me?
你会帮我吗？
Wait. It's okay, it's okay.
等等。很好，很好。
We have time.
我们还来得及。
* SLIPPING THROUGH MY FINGERS *
*指间溜走*
Schoolbag in hand She leaves home in the early morning
清晨她手上拿着书包离开了家门
Waving goodbye With an absentminded smile
带着心不在焉的笑容挥手再见
I watch her go With a surge of that wellknown sadness
我怀着那股熟知的悲伤看着她离开
And I have to sit down for a while
我得坐下来一会儿
The feeling that I'm losing her Forever
那种要永远失去她的感觉
And without really entering her world
还没有真正进入她的世界
I'm glad whenever I can share her laughter
我很高兴可以随时分享她的笑声
That funny little girl
那个有趣的小女孩
Slipping through my fingers all the time
每次都从我指间溜走
I try to capture every minute
每分钟我都想抓住
The feeling in it Slipping through my fingers all the time
它里面的感觉 每次都从我指间溜走
Do I really see what's in her mind?
我真的看到了她的心事吗?
Each time I think I'm close to knowing
每次我认为我就快要知道了
She keeps on growing
她却一直在成长
Slipping through my fingers all the time
每次都从我指间溜走
Sleep in our eyes Her and me at the breakfast table
在我们眼下睡着 她和我坐在早餐桌前
Barely awake I let precious time go by
几乎醒着 我让宝贵的时间流逝
Then when she's gone There's that odd melancholy feeling
当她离开了  有种奇怪的忧郁感觉
And a sense of guilt I can't deny
伴随着一丝负罪感  我却无法否认
What happened to those wonderful adventures
那些其妙的冒险都怎么了
The places I had planned for us to go
那些我打算我们两一起去的地方
Slipping through my fingers all the time
每次都从我指间溜走
Well, some of that we did But most we didn't
其中一些我们去过 但大部分没有
And why, I just don't know
为什么， 我就是不知道
Slipping through my fingers all the time
每次都从我指间溜走
I try to capture every minute
每分钟我都想抓住
The feeling in it Slipping through my fingers all the time
它里面的感觉 每次都从我指间溜走
Do I really see what's in her mind?
我真的看到了她的心事吗?
Each time I think I'm close to knowing
每次我认为我就快要知道了
She keeps on growing
她却一直在成长
Slipping through my fingers all the time
每次都从我指间溜走
Do you think I'm letting you down?
你是不是认为我让你失望了？
Why would you even think that?
你怎么会这么想呢？
Well, because of what you've done.
因为你曾经做过的
I mean, the Dynamos, raising a kid,
我是说，妹力四射，抚养一个孩子成人，
and running a business all on your own.
无依无靠的经营一项事业。
Well, honey, I didn't have a choice.
蜜糖，我没有选择。
I couldn't go home, you know.
我不能回家啊
When I got pregnant, my mother told me not to bother coming back.
当我怀孕的时候，我母亲告诉我别再回去了。
And I wouldn't have had it any other way.
我也不想有其他选择了。
My God, look at what we've had.
我的天，瞧瞧我们都拥有的吧。
Will you give me away?
你会把我托付吗？
Yeah.
很好。
Sometimes I wish That I could freeze the picture
有时我希望我能把画面定格
And save it from the funny tricks of time
躲过时间的那些有趣把戏 把它保存起来
Slipping through my fingers
从我指间溜走
Schoolbag in hand She leaves home in the early morning
清晨她手上拿着书包离开了家门
Waving goodbye With an absentminded smile
带着心不在焉的笑容挥手再见
Donna!
Donna. I need to talk to you about who's giving Sophie away.
Donna。我要跟你谈谈谁会去将Sophie托付出去。
That would be me.         But...
我会。             但是。。。
What about her dad?         Her dad isn't here.
她的爹该怎么办呢？     她的爹不在这里。
It's what she wants. She told me she wants her father here.
那是她想要的。她告诉我她想要她的父亲在场。
What if her father wants that, too?
要是她的父亲也想那样呢？
What? Sam, don't do this now.
什么？Sam,现在别这样做
I can't hear this now!
我现在不能听这个了！
Donna, listen to me. This is about us.
Donna，听我说。这关系着我俩。
* THE WINNER TAKES IT ALL *
赢家通吃
I don't wanna talk
我不想谈论
About things we've gone through
我们已经经历的一切
Though it's hurting me Now it's history
尽管它仍刺痛着我我  现在 它已成历史
I've played all my cards And that's what you've done, too
我已经出完所有的牌 你也是
Nothing more to say No more ace to play
没有什么可说的了  没有Ace可出了
The winner takes it all
赢家通吃
The loser standing small
输家式微
Beside the victory That's her destiny
站在胜利的旁边  那就是她的命运
I was in your arms Thinking I belonged there
我曾经停靠于你的臂湾 以为我属于这里
I figured it made sense Building me a fence
我琢磨着建个围墙会有意义
Building me a home Thinking I'd be strong there
建造一个家园 以为我在里面就会坚强
But I was a fool Playing by the rules
但我是个按照规则出牌的傻瓜
The gods may throw the dice
众神可能只是掷了个骰子而已
Their minds as cold as ice
他们的心灵冷酷若冰霜
And someone way down here Loses someone dear
而下面的某个凡人却失去了他的挚爱
The winner takes it all The loser has to fall
赢家通吃 输家必须倒下
It's simple and it's plain Why should I complain?
就这么简单 这么浅显 为什么我还抱怨呢？
But tell me does she kiss Like I used to kiss you?
但是告诉我 她有像我亲吻你那样吻你吗？
Does it feel the same When she calls your name?
当她呼唤你名字时（你的）感觉还一样吗 ？
Somewhere deep inside You must know I miss you
某个地方的深处 你肯定知道我还想念你
But what can I say? Rules must be obeyed
但是我能说什么呢？规则必须得到遵守
The judges will decide
法官做出的裁决
The likes of me abide
像我这样的人会服从的
Spectators at the show Always staying low
旁听者会依旧低调
The game is on again
游戏又将重复
A lover or a friend
情人抑或友人
A big thing or a small The winner takes it all
大的抑或小的 赢家总是拿走一切
I don't wanna talk 'Cause it makes me feel sad
我不想谈论 因为这让我悲伤
And I understand You've come to shake my hand
我明白 你是来跟我握手致意的
I apologise If it makes you feel bad
如果这让你不好受请接受我的歉意
Seeing me so tense No selfconfidence
看到我这么紧张 没有自信
But you see the winner takes it all
但是你看赢家拿走了全部
The winner takes it all
赢家拿走了全部
The game is on again A lover or a friend
游戏又将重复 情人或是友人
A big thing or a small The winner takes it all
大事抑或小事 赢家总是拿走一切
Donna!
The winner takes it All
赢家拿走了全部
Donna, there you are.
Donna，你在这儿啊。
It's okay.         They're my best shoes.
还好找到了。  这是我最好的鞋呢。
Panic over! Here she is. She's here.
恐慌结束！她来了，在这儿。
Oh, don't worry.         Oh, God.
噢，别担心。     噢，天。
I love you.
我爱你。
Welcome to Sophie and Sky,
欢迎Sophie和SKy,
and to all your friends who have gathered together this evening.
以及今晚到场的各位亲朋好友。
And welcome, especially, to Donna, who represents your family.
特别欢迎Donna，你们家族的代表。
We are all here together in this
我们齐集参加这个
glorious...         And welcome to...
荣耀的。。。  还要欢迎。。。
To Sophie's dad.
SOPHIE她爹。
I have to tell you. He is here.
我得告诉你。他到场了。
I know. I invited him.
我知道。是我邀请的。
You couldn't have. I don't know which one it is.
你不可能。我都不知道是哪个才是。
Oh, my God.
噢，我的天呐。
That's why they're all here!
这就是为什么他们全来了。
I'm sorry. Sorry. I just...
我很抱歉。对不起。我只是。。。
Please, please forgive me! Please forgive me. Please.
求你，原谅我吧！求你原谅我，求你了。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Can you forgive me?         What?
你能原谅我吗？   什么?
I don't care if you slept with hundreds of men.
我不在乎你是否睡过数百个男人。
You're my mom, and I love you so much.
你是我妈，我非常的爱你。
Oh, Soph.
And I haven't slept with hundreds of men.
还有我没有睡过数百个男人。
Am I getting this right?
我理解的没错吧？
Sophie may be mine, but she may be Bill's or Harry's?
Sophie可能是我的，但她也可能是Bill或者Harry的？
Yeah, yeah. That's right. And don't get all self-righteous with me,
对，对，没错。跟我你少来你自由为是
because you have no one but yourself to blame.
因为你只能怪你自己。
Yeah, if you hadn't just dumped my mother
对，如果不是你抛弃了我母亲
and gone off and married somebody else...
一走了之 娶了别人
Hey, hey, wait a minute! I had to go home. I was engaged.
嘿，嘿，等一下！我不的不回家。我订婚了。
But I told Lorraine I couldn't marry her,
但是我告诉Lorraine 我不能娶她
and I came right back.
然后我回来这里。
You... You...
你。。你。。
Why didn't you call me?         Because I was crazy enough
为什么你没有给我电话？  因为我疯到
to think that you would be waiting for me.
以为你会为我守候。
Only when I arrived, they told me you were off with some other guy.
直到我来了之后，他们告诉我你跟其他男人出去了
So, Lorraine called me an idiot
为此，Lorraine说我是个傻瓜
and married me to prove it.
嫁给我证明她是对的。
Sorry, can I just...
抱歉，我可以。。
Oh, Harry, don't... It's all right. You don't have to.
噢，Harry，别。。。没事，你不用这样。
No, no, I just wanted to say it's great to have even a third of Sophie.
不，不，我只想说就算只拥有三分之一的SOPHIE我也心满意足了。
I never thought I'd get even that much of a child.
我从来就没想过能拥有一个孩子那么多。
Donna, you were the first girl I ever loved.
Donna,你是我这辈子爱过的第一个女孩。
Well, actually, you were the last girl I ever loved.
其实，你也是我这辈子爱的最后一个女孩。
Now, this gives me an excuse to come here much more often.
现在，这也给了我一个更常来这儿的理由。
We can find out if you want,
如果你想的话 我们能搞清楚（谁是你父亲）
but I'm with Harry.
但我同意Harry.
Being a third of your dad is great by me.
成为你三分之一的父亲我心满意足了。
By me, too.
我也是。
I'll take a third.
我认养三分之一。
Typical, isn't it? You wait 20 years for a dad,
太典型了。你等一个父亲等了20年，
and then three come along at once.
现在好了 一下等来三个。
Dearly beloved...
挚爱的
You know, I have no clue which one of you is my dad,
我不知道到底哪个是我的父亲，
but I don't mind.
但我不介意
Now, I know what I really want.
现在我知道我到底想要什么了。
Sky, let's just not get married yet.
SKY，我们先别结婚吧。
What?
什么？
You never wanted this anyway.
你根本就不想这样。
I know that. Let's just get off this island
我知道。我们一起离开这个岛吧
and just see the world. Okay? All right?
环游世界。好不好？
I love you.
Donna, do I take it the wedding is cancelled?
Donna,这样看来我是不是可以认为婚礼被取消了？
I'm not entirely sure what's happening right now.
我也不是完全确定到底发生了什么。
Hang on.
等一下。
Why waste a good wedding?
为什么要浪费这个好婚礼呢？
How about it, Sheridan?
你看怎么样，Sheridan?
You're going to need someone to boss around on this island of yours.
在这个属于你的岛上你会需要某个人可以随叫随到 供你差遣
Are you nuts? I am not a bigamist.
你疯了吗？我不是重婚犯。
Neither am I. I'm a divorced man who's loved you for 21 years,
我也不是。我是一个爱了你21年，已经离婚的男人。
and ever since the day I set foot on this island,
自从我踏上这个岛的那天起，
I've been trying to tell you how much I love you.
我就一直努力想要告诉你我有多么的爱你。
Come on, Donna. It's only the rest of your life.
答应我吧，Donna。只是你的余生而已。
* I DO, I DO, I DO, I DO, I DO *
*我愿意，我愿意，我愿意，我愿意*
I can't conceal it
我无法隐藏
Don't you see?
你还没看出来吗？
Can't you feel it?
你还没有感觉到吗？
Say I do
说我愿意
I do, I do, I do, I do, I do
我愿意，我愿意，我愿意，我愿意
Donna, please show it
Donna,求你表态吧
You love me And you know it
你爱我 你也知道
Say I do
说我愿意
I do
我愿意
I do, I do,
我愿意，我愿意
I do, I do.
I now pronounce you man and wife.
我现在宣布你们结为夫妻。
I'm so happy!
我好开心啊！
* WHEN ALL IS SAID AND DONE *
*当所有都已尘埃落定*
Here's to us One more toast And then we'll pay the bill
再祝一次酒 然后我们就去埋单
Deep inside both of us Could feel the autumn chill
我们两的内心都能感到瑟瑟秋意
Birds of passage You and me We fly instinctively
无拘无束 我们俩直觉的在飞
When the summer's over And the dark clouds hide the sun
当夏天末了 乌云遮天蔽日
Neither you nor I'm to blame When all is said and done
问心无愧 当所有都已尘埃落定
In our lives We have walked Some strange and lonely treks
在我们的生活中 我们都曾走过一些奇怪 孤独的旅途
Slightly worn but dignified
些许疲惫但旧高傲
And not too old for sex
而且还没老到不能做爱
Clearheaded and openeyed With nothing left untried
深谙世事 大开眼界 没有不曾尝试过的
Standing calmly at the crossroads No desire to run
平静的站在十字路口 不想再跑下去了
There's no hurry any more When all is said and done
不用再匆忙了 当所有都已尘埃落定
Standing calmly at the crossroads No desire to run
平静的站在十字路口 不想再跑下去了
There's no hurry any more when all is said And done
不用再匆忙了 当所有都已尘埃落定
That's not for me. I'm a writer. Lone wolf.
那不适合我。我是个作家。独狼。
If you change your mind
如果你改了心意
I'm the first in line
我就排在第一个
Honey, I'm still free
甜心，我还是自由身
Take a chance on me
给我一个机会吧
Sorry.
If you need me, let me know I'm gonna be around
如果你需要我，告诉我 我就会来到
If you got no place to go If you're feeling down
如果你无处可去 如果你感到忧伤
Speech!
我要讲话！
I'm gonna make a speech, everybody.
我要讲话,各位。
Yeah, get ready.
准备好。
* TAKE A CHANCE ON ME *
给我一个机会吧
If you're all alone When the pretty birds have flown
如果你在所有漂亮的鸟都飞走之后依旧独身
Honey, I'm still free Take a chance on me
甜心，我还是自由身 给我一个机会吧
Gonna do my very best And it ain't no lie
我会尽我全力 这不是谎言
If you put me to the test If you let me try
如果你要把我考验 如果你让我尝试
Take a chance on me
给我一个机会吧
We can go dancing
我们可以去跳舞
We can go walking As long as we're together
我们可以去走步 只要我们在一起
Listen to some music
听些音乐
Maybe just talking
也许只是说话
You'd get to know me better
你会更加了解我
'Cause you know I've got So much that I wanna do
因为你知道 我有太多太多想要做
When I dream I'm alone with you
当我梦到 我个你单独在一起
It's magic
这就是魔术
You want me to leave it there Afraid of a love affair
你想我放弃它 害怕一段爱情
But I think you know
但我以为你知道
That I can't let go
我不会放手的
If you're all alone When the pretty birds have flown
如果你在所有漂亮的鸟都飞走之后依旧独身
Honey, I'm still free Take a chance on me
甜心，我还是自由身 给我一个机会吧
Gonna do my very best And it ain't no lie
我会尽我全力 这不是谎言
If you put me to the test
如果你要把我考验 如果你让我尝试
If you let me try Take a chance on me
如果你让我试的话  给我一个机会吧
Take a chance on me
给我一个机会吧
It's Aphrodite!
是爱神 维纳斯(罗马神话）！
* MAMMA MIA *
Mamma mia Here I go again
妈妈咪呀感觉又来了
My, my How can I resist you?
我要怎样才能抵抗你呢？
Mamma mia Does it show again?
妈妈咪呀 又出现了吗？
My, my Just how much I've missed you?
我有多么想念你呀
Yes, I've been broken-hearted Blue since the day we parted
是啊，我曾经伤透了心 自分开那天起一直郁闷
Why, why did I ever let you go?
为什么会眼睁睁放你走？
Mamma mia Now I really know
妈妈咪呀我现在知道了
My, my I should not have let you go
我不该错放你的手
* I HAVE A DREAM *
I have a dream
我有一个梦想
A song to sing To help me cope With anything
唱这么一首歌 能助我克服万难
If you see the wonder
如果你见过童话中的
Of a fairy tale
奇迹
You can take the future
你就能掌握未来
Even if you fail
即使你失败了
I believe in angels
我相信天使
Something good in everything I see
我看到的任何东西里都有好的一面
I believe in angels
我相信天使
When I know the time is right for me
当我知道我的时机到了
I'll cross the stream
我就会跨过这条小溪
I have a dream
我有一个梦想
I'll cross the stream
我会跨过这条小溪
I have a dream
我有一个梦想
* DANCING QUEEN *
You can dance
你能舞动
You can jive
你能摇摆
Having the time of your life
享受你的风华正茂
See that girl
看那女孩
Watch that scene
此情此景
Dig in the dancing queen
摇摆皇后驾到
Friday night and the lights are low
礼拜五晚上灯光昏暗
Looking out for a place to go
四处寻找
Where they play the right music
放着合意舞曲的地方
Getting in the swing
融入摇摆的人群
You come to look for a king
你来这找你的国王
Anybody could be that guy
谁都可能是命中注定的那位
Night is young and the music's high
夜未央 舞正酣
With a bit of rock music Everything is fine
只要来点摇滚 万事大吉
You're in the mood for a dance
你正有摇摆的冲动
And when you get the chance
当你抓住机会
You are the dancing queen
你就是摇摆皇后
Young and sweet Only seventeen
年轻貌美十七
Dancing queen
摇摆皇后
Feel the beat from the tambourine
感受着节奏
Oh, yeah
You can dance
你能舞动
You can jive
你能摇摆
Having the time of your life
享受你的风华正茂
See that girl
看那女孩
Watch that scene
此情此景
Dig in the dancing queen
摇摆皇后驾到
Bye.         Bye.
You want another one?
还想再来一曲？
Do you want another one?
你们还想再来一曲？
Let's give it to them!         You want another one?
那我们就再来一曲吧！  你想要吗？
Let's rip it up!
那我们上吧！
* WATERLOO *
滑铁卢
My, my, at Waterloo Napoleon did surrender
啊，拿破仑在滑铁卢投了降
Oh, yeah And I have met my destiny
噢耶， 我也遭遇了我的命运
In quite a similar way
以极其相似的方式
The history book on the shelf
书架上放着历史书
Is always repeating itself
是不是总是重复自己呢
Waterloo I was defeated, you won the war
我在滑铁卢被打败，你赢得了这场战争
Waterloo Promise to love you for ever more
滑铁卢 答应我要爱我到永远
Waterloo Couldn't escape if I wanted to
滑铁卢 就算我想逃避也不行
Waterloo Knowing my fate is to be with you
滑铁卢 知道我的命运就是和你在一起
Waterloo Finally facing my Waterloo
滑铁卢 终于遭遇我的滑铁卢
And how could I ever refuse
我为什么就没有拒绝
I feel like I win when I lose
我输了也有胜利的感觉
Waterloo I was defeated, you won the war
我在滑铁卢被打败，你赢得了这场战争
Waterloo Promise to love you for ever more
滑铁卢 答应我要爱我到永远
Waterloo Couldn't escape if I wanted to
滑铁卢 就算我想逃避也不行
Waterloo Knowing my fate is to be with you
滑铁卢 知道我的命运就是和你在一起
Waterloo Finally facing my Waterloo
滑铁卢 终于遭遇我的滑铁卢
* THANK YOU FOR THE MUSIC *